Simon Rose

Researcher & Software Engineer

simon-rose.co.uk



+447791863017

Profile

Ambitious researcher and software engineer experienced in designing and conducting research, developing games, websites and enterprise applications and teaching computer science at primary, secondary and undergraduate level. Possessing several years of software developing industry and university lecturing experience, strong interpersonal skills and exceptional organisation, planning and time management skills.

Education

PhD in Computer Science - Sheffield Hallam University

Oct 2016 - Sept 2019

Thesis Title: Developing Children's Computational Thinking Skills using Programming

Games

Supervisors: Dr Jacob Habgood and Dr Tim Jay

MComp Software Engineering - Sheffield Hallam University

Sept 2011 - July 2016

First Class (Honours)

Award Classification Mark: 86.55%

A-Levels - King Ecgbert School Sixth Form

Sept 2009 - June 2011

English Literature (A) ICT (B) Product Design (B)

Experience

Associate Lecturer - Sheffield Hallam University

Sept 2016 - Present

- Preparing and delivering teaching content on a number of undergraduate
 Computer Science and Software Engineering modules.
- Supervising BSc and BEng students on their Final Year Projects.
- Student voice 'outstanding' member of staff 2016-17

Computing Teacher - Mercia Secondary School

Jan 2019 - July 2019

- Preparing and delivering content in-line with the computing national curriculum.

Full Stack Software Engineer - 3Squared

Sept 2013 - May 2016

- Developing bespoke web applications in C# using ASP.NET MVC and Web Forms.
- Working with a variety of web technologies including HTML, JavaScript and CSS.

Skills

- CSS (LESS and SASS)

Programming Languages SDK/Frameworks/Software **Other Skills** - Node.js - Organised - JavaScript (and TypeScript) - Angular - Motivated - C++ - React - Pragmatic - Python - .NET - Adaptable - Java - MongoDB - Able to lead - SQL - Photoshop - Business awareness - PHP - Widely-read - InDesign - Fireworks - Presentations - HTML

Publications

Rose, S. P., Habgood, M. P. J., & Jay, T. (2019). Using Pirate Plunder to Develop Children's Abstraction Skills in Scratch. In CHI 2019 Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, 1-6.

Rose, S. P., Habgood, M. P. J., & Jay, T. (2018) Pirate Plunder: Game-Based Computational Thinking Using Scratch Blocks, In Proceedings of the 12th European Conference for Game Based Learning, 556–564.

Rose, S. P., Habgood, M. P. J., & Jay, T. (2017). An Exploration of the Role of Visual Programming Tools in the Development of Young Children's Computational Thinking. Electronic Journal of E-Learning, 15(4), 297–309.

Rose, S. P. (2016). Bricolage Programming and Problem Solving Ability in Young Children: An Exploratory Study. In Proceedings of the 10th European Conference for Game Based Learning, 914-921.

Projects

Pirate Plunder Sept 2017 - Present

- Educational block-based programming game.
- Teaches children how and why to use procedures.
- MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node) stack.
- Developed as part of my PhD.

Dimbot Sept 2015 - Dec 2015

- Visual programming game for children.
- MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node) stack.
- Developed as part of my Masters degree.

Sliding Home Sept 2014 - May 2015

- Lead programmer on a mobile game developed using Marmalade SKD in C++.
- Team of 4, 3 programmers and 1 artist.

Interests

Sport

I enjoy playing and watching sport, primarily football and resistance work in the gym. I play 6-a-side football regularly.

Reading

I like to read widely, I am always striving to broaden my knowledge and understanding both academically and non-academically. I set myself the goal to read a book a week in 2016 and have continued to exceed this target each year.

Music

I played bass guitar in a band for 4 years and have recorded songs and played live. I also enjoy going to music events with friends and listening to music.

References

Dr Jacob Habgood

Reader in Game Development Sheffield Hallam University j.habgood@shu.ac.uk Mr James Fox

Commercial Director 3Squared james.fox@3squared.com